Joao Neiva

Full Stack Developer

Salvador, Brazil | (+55) 71 9 9102-2516 | jg.neiva@gmail.com github.com/ojoaoneiva | linkedin.com/in/ojoaoneiva/

Resumo

Full Stack Developer, I worked remotely in the USA as a volunteer front-end developer, and I'm trained by Labenu's bootcamp, where I built practical projects focusing on technologies such as React, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, and others.

Additionally, I have a Bachelor's degree in Architecture and Urbanism, and I have worked in the construction industry managing teams, collaborating on group projetcs, resolving conflicts, and optimizing processes. I had some experiencies with BIM softwares to automate architectural projects, and through this experience I found the motivation to make a career transition.

Skills

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React.JS, Styled Components, React Hooks, Git, GitHub, Next.JS, Python, Node Js, Typescript, SQL, MySQL, Unity testing, REST, Api Restful, HTTP, Jest, Knex, AWS, Firebase

Education

LABENU (03/2023 – 08/2023) – Web Full-Stack development Bootcamp

A program with over 1000 hours of pratical experience, guided by agile methodologies (Kanban/Scrum). Among the skills learned during the course are: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React.JS, Styled-Components, React Hooks, REST, Api Restful, HTTP, Jest, Node.JS, Knex, TypeScript, MySQL, AWS, SQL, Git, GitHub, Firebase, Unit Testing, and UI Design.

UFBA - Federal University of Bahia (06/2016 - 12/2022) - Bachelor of Architecture and Urbanism

Projects

Social Network - 08/2023

A full-Stack application with a mobile-first frontend for a small social network platform, and a backend that builds an API with database to create users, posts, comments and likes.

Link: github.com/ojoaoneiva/labeddit

E-commerce Frontend -05/2023

A responsive e-commerce website for space-themed products, with a shopping cart, search filters and product's sorting. Built using: React JS , Styled-Components.

Link: github.com/ojoaoneiva/projeto-frontendreact

Landing Page – 04/2023

A responsive website with user interactions, designed for a company focused on university housing. Built using: HTML, CSS e Javascript.

Link: github.com/ojoaoneiva/projeto-landing-page

Work experience

Frontend Developer – (08/2023 – 09/2023) – Holistic Kids Foundation

Worked in web development as a volunteer, using React and Design System, and connecting its features with the backend team.

Intern Architect – (02/2022 – 06/2022) – Pedrosa Engenharia

Team management and process optimization, communication with clientes, suppliers, and labor force, conflict management and construction site monitoring.